TANVEER WAHID

tan@wahid.email • (631) 702-5770 • LinkedIn URL • Sparks, NV • GitHub • Stack Overflow • Website

Vice President of Engineering

Outcome-driven transformational servant leader with a holistic understanding of the software development life cycle. Proven success over 10 years of professional experience in enterprise IT. Experienced in all facets of software development within diverse sectors. Known for execution of multi-million-dollar projects from ideation to completion, introducing Flagship platform, improving uptime for mission-critical cloud applications, and offering consultancy to c-level executives. Collaborative communicator skilled at creating effective relationships at all levels.

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

Tools: PHP, JavaScript, TypeScript, Rust, Python, React, Laravel, Angular, AngularJS, .NET

Xamarin, MySQL/SQL, AWS, CloudFormation/Terraform, Bash, Hardhat/Solidity, Docker

Software Development Life Cycle, Complex Problem Resolution, Agile Development,

Competencies: Technical Project Management, Distributed Ledger Technology (DLT), Mobile Engineering,

Cloud Computing, Cybersecurity, Web3 Tech, Program Management, ISO/NIST Standards,

SaaS Web Applications, RESTful APIs

KEY CAREER HIGHLIGHTS

- Secured 40% while enhancing security, reliability, fault tolerance of critical health cloud applications.
- Ensured 99.99%+ annual uptime for mission-critical cloud applications with zero downtime deployments.
- Delivered Flagship healthcare logistics platform, acquired by major healthcare information technology vendor.
- Co-developed diabetes platform which exceeded expectations lowering A1C by over one point in trials.
- Released three open-source projects in python, rust, and PHP focusing on next-generation technology.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

iDialogs, LLC, Xenia, OH

Vice President, Engineering (2020 – Present)

2014 - Present

Collaborate with acquiring partner's cloud team to execute product acquisition transition for enterprise infrastructure rollout. Partner with executive team on business development and expanding strategies as well as reported to CEO and CTO directly. Coordinate with CEO, entrepreneur, former MIT professor, and former Chief Scientist at Hewlett-Packard on product vision, direction, and market opportunities. Analyze new technologies to determine potential applications in healthcare.

Noted Accomplishments:

- Program management for steering various teams across multiple enterprise organizations and disciplines including DevOps, IT Operations, software development, and API integrations.
- Successfully led development and execution of multiple projects based on mobile, web application, DevOps, and API integrations for enterprise clients in highly regulated industry.
- Coordinated with management on OKRs for future products including vision, mission, purpose, and TBL.

Partner, Software Architect & DevOps (2017 – 2020)

Built and executed cross-platform application of Android and iOS based on Xamarin platform while serving as Lead Architect. Supported in rapid development and implementation of software updates to aid healthcare workers during COVID-19 pandemic. Directed development teams across multiple projects and disciplines, including DevOps, API integrations, mobile development, and web application development.

Noted Accomplishments:

- Acted as HIPAA Security Officer ensuring annual success for security and compliance KPIs.
- Headed cybersecurity initiatives to proactively train, educate, and empower employees.
- Co-authored HIPAA policies based on HITRUST CSF to meet organizational and regulatory compliance.

Senior Software Engineer (2014 – 2017)

Oversaw team for backend development and API integrations. Streamlined recruitment process for hiring new engineers and implemented employee retention strategies to meet long-term goals of company.

Noted Accomplishments:

- Led, trained, empowered, enabled multiple engineers in attaining leadership positions.
- Pioneered patient engagement using lexical preference chat processing and proactive health messaging.

Additional Experience

Advisory Board Member - Cybersecurity Program, Ithaca College - Ithaca, NY (2020 - Present)

• Revamped certification program by attending annual board meetings and providing appropriate feedback.

Senior Software Engineer, Pixafy, Inc. – New York, NY (2013 – 2014)

Lead developer for multiple preliminary initiatives during early development of iDialogs

Senior Web Developer, Don Jagoda Associates, Inc. – Melville, NY (2011 – 2013)

- Built revenue management system to support Staples in modernizing sales reporting across 1500 stores.
- Optimized website traffic campaigns for fortune companies, including P&G, VW, and Charter Bank.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration (2021) | GPA: 3.97

Southern New Hampshire University, Manchester, NH President's List, Winter & Summer Semester (2021)

CERTIFICATIONS

Coursera Blockchain: Foundations and Use Cases (2022) | CompTIA Cybersecurity Analyst (CySA+) (2020 – 2023) | CompTIA Security+ (2020 – 2023) | CompTIA Network+ (2020 – 2023) | AWS Certified Developer (2020 – 2023) | AWS Solutions Architect (2020 – 2023) | Cybersecurity Certificate – Ithaca College Ithaca, NY (2020) | PRINCE2 Agile Foundation – PeopleCert (2020) | ITIL4 Foundation – PeopleCert (2020) | SCRUM Master (PSM1) – Scrum.org (2020)

AFFILIATIONS

Member, The National Society of Leadership and Success 2021 Advisory Board Member, Ithaca College 2020-Present

OPEN-SOURCE PROJECTS

xrpl-rust, A 100% Rust library to interact with the XRPL – <u>GitHub URL</u> phpblock, A lightweight asynchronous PHP server/client for blockchain networks. – <u>GitHub URL</u> fasteth, A fast, asynchronous, python Ethereum RPC client. – GitHub URL